# Atit Gaonkar

(480)-406-0274 • atit-gaonkar.me • linkedin.com/in/atit-gaonkar • github.com/asgaonkar • atit.sgaonkar@gmail.com

#### **Summary**

A highly organized computer science graduate student with strong background in information and application security. Extensive firsthand experience developing and testing binaries, web applications and network devices. Excels as both individual contributor and in teamwork settings, by delivering tasks on-time and to specification.

#### **Education**

Master of Science in Computer Science - Arizona State University, Tempe

Aug 2019 - May 2021

Courses: Software Security, Applied Cryptography, Computer and Network Forensics

3.78 / 4.0 GPA

**Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering** 

June 2014 – May 2018

Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai

8.98 / 10.0 GPA

#### **Technical Skills**

Skillset: Python scripting, binary analysis, application security, traffic & vulnerability management, web security

**Software:** gdb, ghidra, Wireshark, aircrack-ng, john-the-ripper, nmap, Power BI, TIBCO Spotfire

CTF: Participated in numerous Capture the flag events. Member of PwnDevils

Language: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP and SQL

#### Certification

Certified Ethical Hacker - EC Council (CEHv9): Number: ECC67924018402 Name: Atit Shivram Gaonkar

Oct 2017

### **Relevant Experience**

## Software Risk and Compliance (Intern) - FireBird SRC-LLC

Jun 2020 – Present

- Assisted with Information Security Governance Risk and Compliance (PCI-DSS, HIPPA) related activities. Conducted research of industry best practices to assist in the development of or in updating information security policies.
- Analyzed and suggested security policies, processes, and standards to be in accordance with Security Compliance.

#### Data Engineer (Intern) - Tulip Diagnostics, Goa, India

Jan 2019 - Apr 2019

- Analyzed internal processes, business operation and sales structure to create dynamic info-graphic dashboards using various Microsoft's business intelligence tools, SSAS, SSIS, SSRS, TIBCO Spotfire and Power BI.
- Automated the process of interpreting dashboards and forecasting projected revenue using VBA and SQL. Redesigned reporting system resulting in increased efficiency of 81.25%, hence reducing the time spent on month-end analysis.

## Information Security Assistant (Intern) - Tulip Diagnostics, Goa, India

Jan 2019 - Apr 2019

- Worked Closely with Database Administrators and Network Manager to establish security guidelines and practices.
- Executed regular network evaluation and vulnerability scans. Significantly improved security processes.

#### **Academic Projects**

## The Hungry Customer – Restaurant Recommender [@Arizona State University] [\*Current]

Spring 2020

• For all the foodies, who love to try out different food items, this platform provides various restaurant recommendation and based on state wise trending food items. Analyzing sentiments of user reviews to better understand the quality of food and recommend best restaurants based on heuristic measures.

### BinExploit - Binary Exploitation & Reverse Engineering [@Arizona State University]

Fall 2019

- Reverse engineered ELF binaries to exploit the underlying vulnerability. Efficiently patched and synchronized the binaries with the server. Utilized various open source tools for shellcodes to deconstruct and exploit the binaries.
- Used gdb, gef, ghidra to reverse engineer the binaries. Implemented defense in depth strategy while patching.

# PCAP Splitter - Network traffic file splitter [@Arizona State University]

Fall 2019

- Designed a CTF network utility capable of splitting a huge PCAP (network traffic) file into smaller separate TCP or UDP connections based on source and destination IP and port, along with user defined inputs.
- Employed packet inspection scheme differentiating the content to understand the nature of the packet.

#### Multify - A virtual Hotspot [@Personal]

Spring 2018

• Devised a hotspot script to enable a Wi-Fi recipient (laptop/desktop) to simultaneously work as Wi-Fi host, hence acting as an intermediate router. Countered the issue of maximum user connection to a Wi-fi network.